Guide to the Business Office, Yale University Library, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Business Office, Yale University Library, records
1763-1984
RU 735
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.75
The records consist of correspondence, statements, endowment and gift files, and memoranda documenting financial transactions of the Yale University Library Business Office.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-C (YRG 32-C), Records of Yale University Library departments and offices.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Conditions Governing Access
The records were transferred from the Business Office, 1985, 2007.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, statements, endowment and gift files, and memoranda documenting financial transactions of the Yale University Library Business Office.
Academic libraries -- Finance; Yale University. Library
- Business Office records, 1968-1984; Accession 1985-A-061
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019
  - Bawnan map (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Beinecke financial reports - five year projection (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Beinecke history, comprehensive (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cerutti collection purchase (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Connecticut Academy (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cuneiform Inscriptions, BABYLONIAN COLLECTION (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Dues procedure (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Equipment, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Equipment requests, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Equipment requests, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Equipment requests, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Film-Yale collection of classics (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Gimbel Dickens catalogue (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Houghton Mifflin, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Humanities Institute (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Human relations area files (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Macdonald, Dwight papers (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Marinetti (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Microfilm committee report, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Northeast Academic Science - Information Center (NASIC) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Phantasmagorey catalogue (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Publications office procedures (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Recycling (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Research Libraries International, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Network -- invoices general correspondence (RLIN\), 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Research Libraries International Network (RLIN) (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Research Libraries International Network (RLIN) procedures and policies and general information, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Ripley exchange, "Rails of the World": paintings borrowed from Smithsonian (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Room assignments - SML (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - TIAA Studies (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Walling, Ana Strunsky-papers (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Library endowment fund card file, 1763-1963; Accession 2008-A-083
  Scope and Contents
  Arranged alphabetically by last name.
  - Brush Collection, Sheffield Scientific School (Box 1)
  - Cincinnati Society Deposit (Box 1)
  - Class of 1872, Yale College, Fund (Box 1)
  - Class of 1884, Yale College, Fund (Box 1)
  - Class of 1896, Yale College, Fund (Box 1)
  - Class of 1899, Yale College, Fund (Box 1)
  - Class of 1943 Memorial Fund (Box 1)
  - Dwight Hall Fund (Box 1)
  - General Fund (Box 1)
  - German Seminary Library, German Seminar (Box 1)
  - Map Collection Endowment (Box 1)
  - Microtext Purchase Fund (Box 1)
  - Moffat, Douglas M., Yale 1903 (Box 1)
  - New York Alumni Association Fund (Box 1)
  - Reed, Edward Bliss, Carol Collection (Box 1)
  - Toumey, James W., Memorial Library, School of Forestry (Box 1)
  - Trowbridge Reference Library, Divinity School (Box 1)
  - Woolsey, Heathcote (Box 1)
  - Yale Alumni Association of Long Island Fund (Box 1)